<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on crashdot.com</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on crashdot.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 23:01:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transactional updates on OpenSUSE Tumbleweed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/transactional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 13:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/transactional/</guid>
      <description>It’s possible to use transactional or atomic updates on OpenSUSE Tumbleweed and leveraging the snapshot capabilities of btrfs. It’s actually quite simple; all you need to do is to install the command using zipper.&#xA;Important prerequisite: the filesystem must be btrfs.&#xA;sudo zypper in transactional-update This will install the command. Next you want to set up some, to prevent some potential issues.&#xA;# Note: this systemd service is required to create RPM dirs in /var as TU # does not mount /var in the new snapshot to maintain atomicity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>systemd-boot on OpenSUSE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sdboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 23:01:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sdboot/</guid>
      <description>I am weird sometimes, I know. Ever since I used Pop!OS, which uses systemd-boot as default boot manager, I have fallen in love with it. The simplicity and speed of systemd-boot versus the complexity and bulk of GRUB2 just won me over.&#xA;Mind you, GRUB2 is very good at what it does. It’s just that I don’t need all it does. All I need is to boot my machine, nothing more, nothing less.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing dotfiles using stow on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dotfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dotfiles/</guid>
      <description>One thing that’s always a bit of a pain when you use multiple computers, or when you want to reinstall your computer at some point in time is that you have to recreate your configuration files or ‘dotfiles’ to have everything back as you want again.&#xA;There are several ways of doing this, but recently I came across a little tool called GNU stow. It is a much easier way of managing dotfiles than for instance using a git bare repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested distributions under WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 22:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>The following distributions I have installed/created, tested and used under WSL2 and Windows 10.&#xA;Alpine Linux; extremely tiny; created from Docker image AlmaLinux; migrated from CentOS using AlmaLinux migration tool Arch Linux; created from virtual machine install CentOS 7; created from rootfs image, then upgraded to latest version CentOS 8; Upgraded from CentOS7 CentOS Stream; upgraded from from CentOS8 install Deepin Linux; created from virtual machine install Debian 10 (Buster); Microsoft Store Debian Testing (Bullseye); upgraded from official Debian 10 release Devuan; migrated from Debian as installed from the Microsoft Store Fedora; created from virtual machine installation Gentoo; compiled from source using Stage3 tarball/rootfs iamge Kali Linux; Microsoft Store Oracle Linux; migrated from CentOS instance using CentOS migration tool from Oracle RedHat Enterprise Linux; created from virtual machine installation Rocky Linux; migrated from CentOS using RockyLinux migration tool Ubuntu; Microsoft Store Slackware; created from Docker image As you can see, if you can find your favorite distribution in the Microsoft Store, great, if not or if its only available as a paid distribution, just bake your own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A couple little Windows things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/little-windows-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 13:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/little-windows-things/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a discussion on a forum on the usefulness of virtual desktops and the implementation on Windows 10. Now everyone can have their opinions on virtual desktops and I do as well, but in that discussion some things came up that are apparently not so well known.&#xA;Some people find it cumbersome to switch between virtual desktops to the point it becomes unusable for them. They need to go to Task View (WIN+TAB), then use the mouse to click the desktop they want.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any Linux distribution on Windows 10 with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a Linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a lightweight hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 is required.&#xA;An explanation on how to enable WSL2 support can be found on the page detailing how to create a Gentoo instance on WSL2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo on Windows with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gentoo-on-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gentoo-on-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 or newer is required.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo is an open-source project and lives by the work of its contributors. There are plenty of open issues, and we need your help to make Hugo even more awesome. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be a Go guru to contribute to the project&amp;rsquo;s development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a fast and modern static site generator written in Go, and designed to make website creation fun again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
