<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>crashdot.com</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on crashdot.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:52:22 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transactional updates on OpenSUSE Tumbleweed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/transactional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 13:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/transactional/</guid>
      <description>It’s possible to use transactional or atomic updates on OpenSUSE Tumbleweed and leveraging the snapshot capabilities of btrfs. It’s actually quite simple; all you need to do is to install the command using zipper.&#xA;Important prerequisite: the filesystem must be btrfs.&#xA;sudo zypper in transactional-update This will install the command. Next you want to set up some, to prevent some potential issues.&#xA;# Note: this systemd service is required to create RPM dirs in /var as TU # does not mount /var in the new snapshot to maintain atomicity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing dotfiles using stow on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dotfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dotfiles/</guid>
      <description>One thing that’s always a bit of a pain when you use multiple computers, or when you want to reinstall your computer at some point in time is that you have to recreate your configuration files or ‘dotfiles’ to have everything back as you want again.&#xA;There are several ways of doing this, but recently I came across a little tool called GNU stow. It is a much easier way of managing dotfiles than for instance using a git bare repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSUSE Tumbleweed, 6 months in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opensuse/opensuse-tumbleweed-6-months-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 23:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opensuse/opensuse-tumbleweed-6-months-in/</guid>
      <description>Well, here we are, 6 months after installing OpenSUSE Tumbleweed and still no urge to change. The only change I am longing for is the update to KDE Plasma 6, which should be coming soon now that it has officially been released.&#xA;Since there are basically no updates since my last post in December, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to say. I did however made some changes. A couple of weeks ago, my GTX1080 decided to shit itself such that it triggers the short protection in the power supply so that&amp;rsquo;s out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>systemd-boot on OpenSUSE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sdboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 23:01:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sdboot/</guid>
      <description>I am weird sometimes, I know. Ever since I used Pop!OS, which uses systemd-boot as default boot manager, I have fallen in love with it. The simplicity and speed of systemd-boot versus the complexity and bulk of GRUB2 just won me over.&#xA;Mind you, GRUB2 is very good at what it does. It’s just that I don’t need all it does. All I need is to boot my machine, nothing more, nothing less.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSUSE: 4 months in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opensuse/opensuse-4-months-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opensuse/opensuse-4-months-in/</guid>
      <description>Maybe it is time for a little update, even if there is not much to say. After 4 months of running OpenSUSE Tumbleweed, I can honestly say I have not had a single moment where I&amp;rsquo;d thought I should maybe look for another distribution because XYZ is getting too annoying.&#xA;Of course it does have some annoyances. Some are with me, like running systemd-boot while it is not officially ready for primetime yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interesting (or: first tiling windows manager experience)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/opensuse/nteresting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/opensuse/nteresting/</guid>
      <description>The other night, I was playing around watching YouTube videos and was watching this one video from Brodie Robertson on how he was now using Hyprland as his daily driver. Usually, I just zone out to other tasks when the topic gets to a tiling window manager, as it is not for me: I have a ultrawide screen on my desktop, with a 3440x1440 resolution and trust me, you do not want to run console fullscreen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No more Windows. FreeBSD instead.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-10-10-no-more-windows-freebsd-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-10-10-no-more-windows-freebsd-instead/</guid>
      <description>No, I did not stop running OpenSUSE Tumbleweed. That&amp;rsquo;s still my daily driver. I did however wipe my Windows drive and installed FreeBSD instead. I have used FreeBSD quite a lot way back when, and since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually booted into Windows for months, I just decided to install FreeBSD on that drive so I could play with it again after I saw KDE is actively supporting FreeBSD for the desktop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end to distro-hopping?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-end-to-distro-hopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 21:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-end-to-distro-hopping/</guid>
      <description>Since I have moved to running Linux basically full time, I have ran Pop!OS, Fedora, Nobara, back to Fedora KDE Spin and now OpenSUSE Tumbleweed. All of them are good distributions and none have any real deal-breakers for me not to want to use them.&#xA;The fact that I really, really like Tumbleweed was not a given. Quite the contrary. OpenSUSE does it&amp;rsquo;s own thing, so it is a bit of a learning curve if you are used to Debian-based or RedHat-based distributions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running redundant AdGuard@Home DNS servers on Synology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/server/running-redundant-adguardhome-dns-servers-on-synology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 12:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/server/running-redundant-adguardhome-dns-servers-on-synology/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick post on how to run multiple instances of AdGuard@Home on a single Synology host using Docker.&#xA;Problem: you cannot easily, using Docker, run multiple instances of the same program - or different program - while listening on the same port.&#xA;Solution: do not use host or bridge networking, but put the container on the same network as the host using macvlan.&#xA;To achieve this, we need to do the following:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New laptop, new Linux distro</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-laptop-new-linux-distro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 14:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-laptop-new-linux-distro/</guid>
      <description>I finally got fed up with my Macbook Pro as a Linux laptop. It was a 2012 model, no longer supported by Apple. But the quirky implementation of Nvidia discrete graphics on the Macbook wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best for reliable Linux operation. Mind you, Nvidia is always a bit of a challenge, but Apple being Apple certainly does not help in that regard.&#xA;Anyway, I am currently sporting a Lenovo T460 from 2016.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring your network or homelab using Zabbix and Grafana</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/monitoring-your-network-or-homelab-using-zabbix-and-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/monitoring-your-network-or-homelab-using-zabbix-and-grafana/</guid>
      <description>For the longest time, I have been monitoring my network and homelab using Observium. This worked and does work very well. Observium is very good at what it does. However, there are a couple of things that do not work so well for me using Observium:&#xA;Observium does not let me add applications to monitor very easily or at all Observium is limited to what can be offered through SNMP Observium is not open source and as such it cannot be modified or changed to your needs Observium is not an application I have come across in my professional life, so knowing how it works does not help me professionally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As short as possible: application containers, system containers, virtualization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/as-short-as-possible/application-containers-system-containers-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 10:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/as-short-as-possible/application-containers-system-containers-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, there is a bit of confusion as to what the difference is between application containers (Docker, Podman, K8S, OpenShift), system containers (LXC/LXD) and virtualization (KVM, Vmware, Hyper-V, Xen) and when you should use them. I will try to explain the differences as short as possible.&#xA;Application containers Application containers are created with the most minimal environment to run a specific application. This includes the OS and all dependencies for that application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did you know... (or, RHEL on LXC/LXD)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/did-you-know/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/did-you-know/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</guid>
      <description>There are no RedHat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) LXC/LXD container images publicly available? There are LXC/LXD container images available for CentOS and Fedora? You can convert a CentOS install to RHEL using the Convert2RHEL tool? This also works for a LXC/LXD container? You will need to do this if you want to run RHEL on Proxmox in a LXC container? You can create a tarbal of a running system to import into a vanilla LXC/LXD installation?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested distributions under WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 22:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>The following distributions I have installed/created, tested and used under WSL2 and Windows 10.&#xA;Alpine Linux; extremely tiny; created from Docker image AlmaLinux; migrated from CentOS using AlmaLinux migration tool Arch Linux; created from virtual machine install CentOS 7; created from rootfs image, then upgraded to latest version CentOS 8; Upgraded from CentOS7 CentOS Stream; upgraded from from CentOS8 install Deepin Linux; created from virtual machine install Debian 10 (Buster); Microsoft Store Debian Testing (Bullseye); upgraded from official Debian 10 release Devuan; migrated from Debian as installed from the Microsoft Store Fedora; created from virtual machine installation Gentoo; compiled from source using Stage3 tarball/rootfs iamge Kali Linux; Microsoft Store Oracle Linux; migrated from CentOS instance using CentOS migration tool from Oracle RedHat Enterprise Linux; created from virtual machine installation Rocky Linux; migrated from CentOS using RockyLinux migration tool Ubuntu; Microsoft Store Slackware; created from Docker image As you can see, if you can find your favorite distribution in the Microsoft Store, great, if not or if its only available as a paid distribution, just bake your own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A couple little Windows things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/little-windows-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 13:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/little-windows-things/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a discussion on a forum on the usefulness of virtual desktops and the implementation on Windows 10. Now everyone can have their opinions on virtual desktops and I do as well, but in that discussion some things came up that are apparently not so well known.&#xA;Some people find it cumbersome to switch between virtual desktops to the point it becomes unusable for them. They need to go to Task View (WIN+TAB), then use the mouse to click the desktop they want.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any Linux distribution on Windows 10 with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a Linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a lightweight hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 is required.&#xA;An explanation on how to enable WSL2 support can be found on the page detailing how to create a Gentoo instance on WSL2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo on Windows with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gentoo-on-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gentoo-on-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 or newer is required.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warsaw, Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photos/warsaw-poland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photos/warsaw-poland/</guid>
      <description>Palace of Culture and Science (Polish: Pałac Kultury i Nauki), is a notable high-rise building in central Warsaw, Poland. With a total height of 237 metres (778 ft) it is the tallest building in Poland, the 5th-tallest building in the European Union (including spire) and one of the tallest on the European continent. Constructed in 1955, it houses various public and cultural institutions such as cinemas, theatres, libraries, sports clubs, university faculties and authorities of the Polish Academy of Sciences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hel, Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photos/hel-poland-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photos/hel-poland-3/</guid>
      <description>Hel Peninsula (Polish: Mierzeja Helska) is a 35-km-long sand bar peninsula in northern Poland separating the Bay of Puck from the open Baltic Sea. The width of the peninsula varies from approximately 300 m near Jurata, through 100 m in the most narrow part to over 3 km at the tip. Since the peninsula was formed entirely of sand, it is frequently turned into an island by winter storms. Until the 17th century the peninsula was a chain of islands that formed a strip of land only during the summer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hel, Poland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photos/hel-poland-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photos/hel-poland-2/</guid>
      <description>Hel Peninsula (Polish: Mierzeja Helska) is a 35-km-long sand bar peninsula in northern Poland separating the Bay of Puck from the open Baltic Sea. The width of the peninsula varies from approximately 300 m near Jurata, through 100 m in the most narrow part to over 3 km at the tip. Since the peninsula was formed entirely of sand, it is frequently turned into an island by winter storms. Until the 17th century the peninsula was a chain of islands that formed a strip of land only during the summer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arizona, US</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photos/arizona-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photos/arizona-us/</guid>
      <description>The Grand Canyon is a steep-sided canyon carved by the Colorado River in Arizona, United States. The canyon is 277 miles (446 km) long, up to 18 miles (29 km) wide and attains a depth of over a mile (6,093 feet or 1,857 meters).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicago, US</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photos/chicago-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photos/chicago-us/</guid>
      <description>Chicago, officially the City of Chicago, is the most populous city in the U.S. state of Illinois, and the third-most-populous city in the United States. With an estimated population of 2,705,994 (2018), it is also the most populous city in the Midwestern United States. Chicago is the county seat of Cook County, the second-most-populous county in the US, with a small portion of the northwest side of the city extending into DuPage County near O&amp;rsquo;Hare Airport.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Panaji, India</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/photos/panaji-india-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/photos/panaji-india-2/</guid>
      <description>Panaji, formerly Panjim, is the capital of the Indian state of Goa and the headquarters of North Goa district. It lies on the banks of the Mandovi River estuary in the Ilhas de Goa sub-district (taluka). With a population of 114,759 in the metropolitan area, Panjim is Goa&amp;rsquo;s largest urban agglomeration, ahead of Margão and Vasco da Gama.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo is an open-source project and lives by the work of its contributors. There are plenty of open issues, and we need your help to make Hugo even more awesome. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be a Go guru to contribute to the project&amp;rsquo;s development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a fast and modern static site generator written in Go, and designed to make website creation fun again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>This is my little corner of the web where I put the articles I write on Linux and other tech. Mostly for my own reference, as I run into things or try to fix something for myself. And if I think it is something someone else could also benefit from, I will put it up.&#xA;Who am I? I am a former IT consultant that started as a UNIX and Linux admin way back in the 90&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
