<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer on crashdot.com</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/computer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer on crashdot.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 21:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/computer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring your network or homelab using Zabbix and Grafana</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/monitoring-your-network-or-homelab-using-zabbix-and-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/monitoring-your-network-or-homelab-using-zabbix-and-grafana/</guid>
      <description>For the longest time, I have been monitoring my network and homelab using Observium. This worked and does work very well. Observium is very good at what it does. However, there are a couple of things that do not work so well for me using Observium:&#xA;Observium does not let me add applications to monitor very easily or at all Observium is limited to what can be offered through SNMP Observium is not open source and as such it cannot be modified or changed to your needs Observium is not an application I have come across in my professional life, so knowing how it works does not help me professionally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As short as possible: application containers, system containers, virtualization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/as-short-as-possible/application-containers-system-containers-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 10:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/as-short-as-possible/application-containers-system-containers-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, there is a bit of confusion as to what the difference is between application containers (Docker, Podman, K8S, OpenShift), system containers (LXC/LXD) and virtualization (KVM, Vmware, Hyper-V, Xen) and when you should use them. I will try to explain the differences as short as possible.&#xA;Application containers Application containers are created with the most minimal environment to run a specific application. This includes the OS and all dependencies for that application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did you know… (or, RHEL on LXC/LXD)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/did-you-know/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/did-you-know/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</guid>
      <description>There are no RedHat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) LXC/LXD container images publicly available? There are LXC/LXD container images available for CentOS and Fedora? You can convert a CentOS install to RHEL using the Convert2RHEL tool? This also works for a LXC/LXD container? You will need to do this if you want to run RHEL on Proxmox in a LXC container? You can create a tarbal of a running system to import into a vanilla LXC/LXD installation?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested distributions under WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 22:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>The following distributions I have installed/created, tested and used under WSL2 and Windows 10.&#xA;Alpine Linux; extremely tiny; created from Docker image AlmaLinux; migrated from CentOS using AlmaLinux migration tool Arch Linux; created from virtual machine install CentOS 7; created from rootfs image, then upgraded to latest version CentOS 8; Upgraded from CentOS7 CentOS Stream; upgraded from from CentOS8 install Deepin Linux; created from virtual machine install Debian 10 (Buster); Microsoft Store Debian Testing (Bullseye); upgraded from official Debian 10 release Devuan; migrated from Debian as installed from the Microsoft Store Fedora; created from virtual machine installation Gentoo; compiled from source using Stage3 tarball/rootfs iamge Kali Linux; Microsoft Store Oracle Linux; migrated from CentOS instance using CentOS migration tool from Oracle RedHat Enterprise Linux; created from virtual machine installation Rocky Linux; migrated from CentOS using RockyLinux migration tool Ubuntu; Microsoft Store Slackware; created from Docker image As you can see, if you can find your favorite distribution in the Microsoft Store, great, if not or if its only available as a paid distribution, just bake your own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A couple little Windows things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/little-windows-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 13:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/little-windows-things/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a discussion on a forum on the usefulness of virtual desktops and the implementation on Windows 10. Now everyone can have their opinions on virtual desktops and I do as well, but in that discussion some things came up that are apparently not so well known.&#xA;Some people find it cumbersome to switch between virtual desktops to the point it becomes unusable for them. They need to go to Task View (WIN+TAB), then use the mouse to click the desktop they want.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any Linux distribution on Windows 10 with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a Linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a lightweight hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 is required.&#xA;An explanation on how to enable WSL2 support can be found on the page detailing how to create a Gentoo instance on WSL2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo on Windows with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gentoo-on-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gentoo-on-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 or newer is required.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
